

# Sam Wood Senior UI Engineer

I'm an experienced web and design system engineer with over a decade of expertise. My background encompasses frontend engineering within design systems and experience in both front and backend web development, resulting in the creation of impactful and user-friendly digital experiences across a diverse range of web solutions.



**Fmail** 

sam.webineer@gmail.com



Phone

(+44) 7921 619 532



LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/samwood23



Address

Bournemouth, UK

### Recent experience



### Unit4

#### Senior UI Engineer

Aug 2022 - Present | ♥ Remote, UK

- Playing a key role in establishing the foundations of the Unit4 design system, Ripple, by building, managing, testing and documenting the design system's core components and code architecture.
- Key contributor in the comprehensive re-architecturing of the component codebase to be exclusively React-based in an agile shift with new business requirements.
- Lead the way in researching, planning and crafting comprehensive design system documentation, with a mindset to ensure inclusivity for all user types and abilities.
- Collaborating closely and effectively with UI designers and design system managers to streamline component development and facilitate constructive feedback loops.
- Undertook ownership and responsibility in the generation of a dynamic React-based documentation website to unite the design system into a reliable single source of truth.
- Providing valuable peer support and coaching of engineering best practices through live collaboration, on-screen demonstrations, and code and design review feedback sessions.
- Leading workshops to support the wider engineering teams to aid adoption and implementation of design system components, features and best practices.



## CHS Agency

#### Senior Web Developer

Sep 2014 - Jul 2022 | Ohristchurch, UK

- Managed all areas of digital output for the creative agency for UK and global brands including HSBC, Mastercard, Allianz, LV= & Openpay.
- Developed an end-to-end bespoke web application platform, providing multi-channel customisable demo presentation features using a combination of PHP, MySQL, CI4, HTML5, CSS and JavaScript/jQuery.
- Built and maintained multiple client and company Wordpress websites, utilising both industry and custom theme builders.
- Implemented, designed and deployed database architecture system with custom user interface admin portal for a UK charity to manage and maintain sponsorship and donations.
- Managed client relationships across digital spaces within the company.

#### Skills

HTML5 • CSS • SASS • Bootstrap
JavaScript • React JS • Typescript
jQuery • Design Systems • Accessibility
PHP • MVC • JSON • Wordpress
GSAP JS animation • Git • Jest
Adobe Suite • Figma • Microsoft Suite

Design systems thinking • Eye for detail Problem-solving • Self management Motivated • Critical thinking

- Constructed and implemented a strategy to deploy digital display solutions through the Google Display network, using JavaScript animation library (GSAP), Google Studio and Google Sheets.
- As a lead, participated in work resourcing, time management and best practices to enable delivering a high standard of digital output for clients.



# Sam Wood Freelance Freelance Web Designer & Developer

2012 - 2014 | • Verwood, UK

- Experience in producing a range of digital solutions including website design, logo & branding, frontend website development, publications and custom backend CMS systems.
- Delivering custom design and development for local clients, most notably the <u>AMERC</u>, Hollybrook Infant School and Bournemouth 7's (build only 2014 edition) websites.
- Demonstrating time and project management whilst building new client relationships.

### Latest projects



# Unit4 **Design System**



Ripple design system of web components and documentation housed in Storybook.

Unit4 Design System



# Openpay **Demo Platform**

Bespoke E2E web demonstration platform for POS payment gateways.

Demo on request

#### Education



Southampton Solent University
First Class BSC (Honours) Web Design

2011 - 2014 | • Southampton, UK



Udemy
React - The Complete Guide 2023